Guide to the "Donald B. Tresidder, Stanford's Overlooked Treasure" Research Materials SC0438
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
"Donald B. Tresidder, Stanford's Overlooked Treasure" research materials
1912-1991
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kiester, Edwin.
SC0438
1.5 Linear Feet
Audio tapes and transcripts of interviews with people who knew or worked with Donald B. Tresidder, 1987-1991; research notes, clippings, and photocopies of source materials, 1912-1991; photographs; and some correspondence of Harry Press, Frederic Glover, and Kiester, 1990-1991. Persons interviewed include Alf E. Brandin, Stuart Cross, Alvin C. Eurich, Ernest R. Hilgard, William Janns, Harry Sanders, Thomas Spragens, and Wallace Stegner.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Edwin Kiester, 1992.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Donald B. Tresidder was president of Stanford University from 1943 to 1948.
Description of the Collection
Audio tapes and transcripts of interviews with people who knew or worked with Donald B. Tresidder, 1987-1991; research notes, clippings, and photocopies of source materials, 1912-1991; photographs; and some correspondence of Harry Press, Frederic Glover, and Kiester, 1990-1991. Persons interviewed include Alf E. Brandin, Stuart Cross, Alvin C. Eurich, Ernest R. Hilgard, William Janns, Harry Sanders, Thomas Spragens, and Wallace Stegner.
Photoprints.; Oral histories.; Phonotapes.; Spragens, Thomas A.; Stegner, Wallace, 1909-1993; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian); Kiester, Edwin.; Kiester, Edwin.; Tresidder, Donald Bertrand; Glover, Frederic O.; Brandin, Alf E.; Cross, Stuart G.; Press, Harry.; Sanders, Harry; Hilgard, Ernest R. (Ernest Ropiequet); Janss, William.
- Transcripts
- Research/Background Materials
- Audio recordings
  - Buma, Maureen, 1991 Jan 25; 2.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Cross, Stuart G., 1990 Jun 21; 2.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Cunha, Irma, 2.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Ditz, John A., 1990 Dec 12; 2.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Griffin, Mary Murray, 1991 May 6; 2.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Hilgard, Ernest R. (Jack), 1991 Jan 23; 2.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Hornby, Rosemary, 1991 Jul 1; 2.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Janss, Bill, 1990 Sep 14; 2.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Janss, Bill, 1991 May 10; 2.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Milton, 1990 Nov 7; 2.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Lee, Russel Hewlett and Lee, Betty, 1991 Apr 30; 2.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Sanders, Harry, 1991 Jun 25; 2.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Skidmore, Mary, 1990 Jun 21; 2.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Stegner, Wallace, 1991 Feb 15; 2.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Turrentine, Lowell, 1990 Jun 27; 2.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Unidentified, 2.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)